# **PELUMI ADETOYE**

# **Front End Developer**

Ikeja, Lagos • pelumiiadetoye@gmail.com • https://github.com/misspelz

#### SUMMARY

An enthusiastic and detail-oriented Front End Developer with a good knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and third-party frameworks/libraries such as React and React Native. I seek to utilize my skills to provide value to projects both today and in the future, and aim to take on new challenges and technologies for developing new features and enhancing the overall user experiences.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

HTML5	React JS
CSS3	React Native
Tailwind CSS	Git/Github
JavaScript	Command line tools

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Front End Developer, ITSkillsCenter

Software Development & Training Agency

- Developed user-friendly web pages with engaging features
- Created reusable codes that is scalable and optimized in performance
- Worked with the version control system, git, to keep track of codes
- Utilized industry best practices for mobile-first and responsive web design
- Participated in team meetings, contributed ideas and solutions

# Front End Developer, Dufuna

2021 - 2022

Nov. 2022 - May 2023

Online Graduate Trainee Program

- Created responsive and functional user interfaces
- Maintained brand consistency throughout the design process
- Worked closely with other team members

#### **EDUCATION**

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun State 2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Science in Physics

#### **PROJECTS**

 Bloggit, a Tech blog website where the User is able to Create, Read, Update, Share and Delete posts. In addition, I created a Store page where Users can gain access to related Books, add to cart, and make payment using flutterwave.

REACT JS and TAILWIND CSS

Github Link: https://github.com/misspelz/blog

Live Link: <a href="https://bloggit.netlify.app/">https://bloggit.netlify.app/</a>

Portfolio Website

— HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT

Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/misspelz/portfolio">https://github.com/misspelz/portfolio</a>
Live Link: <a href="https://portfolio-oluwapelumi.netlify.app/">https://portfolio-oluwapelumi.netlify.app/</a>

Note App, a To Do Application where the User is able to Create, Read, Update, and Delete notes.

- REACT NATIVE

Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/misspelz/Note-App">https://github.com/misspelz/Note-App</a>

- ❖ Facebook Website Clone in collaboration with a Team Member where I created the Add Post, Left Sidebar, Timeline and Profile Page Components.
  - REACT JS and TAILWIND CSS

Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/misspelz/facebook">https://github.com/misspelz/facebook</a> clone

Live Link: <a href="https://facebookwebsiteclone.netlify.app/">https://facebookwebsiteclone.netlify.app/</a>

# **SKILLS/COMPETENCIES**

- Clear communication
- Problem solving
- Responsive design
- Debugging
- Team playing

## **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

- Testing new technologies
- Collaboration
- Researching
- Scrabble
- Monopoly
- Table tennis